<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4001/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4001/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-03-17T00:58:38+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4001/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Murat Sever</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><author><name>Murat Sever</name></author><entry><title type="html">Wireless Signal Processing at the Edge</title><link href="http://localhost:4001/blog/WSP-at-edge/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Wireless Signal Processing at the Edge" /><published>2021-03-17T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2021-03-17T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4001/blog/WSP-at-edge</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4001/blog/WSP-at-edge/">&lt;p&gt;In Digital Signal Processing (DSP) field, traditional learning is mostly built on simulation software like Matlab or Python libraries like numpy and scipy. Students are often given assignments to apply their theoretical knowledge playing with syntatic data. But this approach comes with its shortcomings. First, in real world more factors come into play and signals on-air differ from syntatically generated ones. So, solutions that work on simulation environment must be confirmed to work with real signals as well. Second, in real life signal processing software must keep up with the data rate. Though this may not be a major concern with simulated data, performance and sustainability are critical for the application to be successful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project aims to help students better understand wireless communication systems with hands-on training. Software Defined Radio (SDR) embraces several different technologies which are highly complicated. But it is also a powerful tool to understand wireless communications. SDR powered by Jetson Nano will provide students to apply their theoretical knowledge on real, on-air signals around us. Jetson Nano will be used as computation device for signal processing. Students will capture on-air signals with a low-cost RF front-end like RTL-SDR and apply signal processing techniques to complete assigments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Students will benefit a lot from working with such an environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lectures supported with Jetson-powered labs will enable students to learn difficult concepts easily.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It will improve their programming skills, leveraging both CPU and GPU. Students can use C++ or Python as their programming language.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Because Jetson Nano is a heteregenous computing environment they can further accelerate their code using CUDA programming.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jetson Nano platform also enable them to apply AI on radio frequency domain. Signal processing jobs like modulation recognition or RF fingerprinting can make use of AI.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nvidia has many great online resources accessible for students. Students can learn more by taking courses offered by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nvidia.com/en-us/training/online/&quot;&gt;DLI&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Murat Sever</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="jetson nano" /><category term="SDR" /><summary type="html">In Digital Signal Processing (DSP) field, traditional learning is mostly built on simulation software like Matlab or Python libraries like numpy and scipy. Students are often given assignments to apply their theoretical knowledge playing with syntatic data. But this approach comes with its shortcomings. First, in real world more factors come into play and signals on-air differ from syntatically generated ones. So, solutions that work on simulation environment must be confirmed to work with real signals as well. Second, in real life signal processing software must keep up with the data rate. Though this may not be a major concern with simulated data, performance and sustainability are critical for the application to be successful.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome to my blog!</title><link href="http://localhost:4001/blog/welcome-to-my-blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to my blog!" /><published>2021-03-16T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2021-03-16T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4001/blog/welcome-to-my-blog</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4001/blog/welcome-to-my-blog/">&lt;p&gt;Hi! Nice to see you here where you will find posts on Software Defined Radio (SDR). I will be using Nvidia’s Jetson Nano Developer Kit for DSP processing.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Murat Sever</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="jetson nano" /><category term="SDR" /><summary type="html">Hi! Nice to see you here where you will find posts on Software Defined Radio (SDR). I will be using Nvidia’s Jetson Nano Developer Kit for DSP processing.</summary></entry></feed>